Ahmed Lotfe

Backend Developer

🛮 ahmedlotfe132@gmail.com 📞 01127242839 / 01063523915 🏻 ## 19/08/1996

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmed-lotfe-583a4215a/ https://github.com/Ahmedlotfe

Education

2016 - 2020

15th of May Higher Institute of Engineering

Profile

I'm a Backend developer with two years of experience in web development. Well-acquainted with database engineering.

Knowledgeable in PHP, Python and frameworks such as Laravel, Django and Odoo.

I made many projects using Laravel and Django for web and mobile apps.

Professional Experience

05/2022 - 11/2022

Backend Developer, Agency-IT

- Developed and improved Odoo modules using Python and the Odoo framework
- Created and maintained backend APIs for websites using PHP, Laravel, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and JavaScript
- Collaborated with team members to ensure timely and high-quality project delivery
- Overcame challenges in developing and maintaining complex systems with large amounts of data
- Implemented various features and improvements to enhance system performance and user experience

12/2022 - present

Backend Developer, *United Distributors*

- Developed and maintained an ERP system using PHP, Laravel, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and JavaScript
- Created and improved backend APIs for a mobile app
- Implemented various features and improvements to enhance system performance and user experience
- Overcame challenges in developing and maintaining complex systems with large amounts of data
- Collaborated with team members to ensure timely and high-quality project delivery

Projects

Gym_Management_System □

Gym Management System, Website to Help:

- The owner of the gym to manage the gym by knowing the subscribers in the gym and the expiry date of their subscription through the facial recognition feature.
- Customers to know the advantages of the gym and the ability to subscribe online and buy gym products and learn how to perform exercises and know the appropriate diet for it.
- Trainers by promoting them by placing their information on the web site.

The Gym has an online store:

• I made my own custom user model, categories and products, Carts, Incrementing, Decrementing and removing cart items, Unlimited Product image gallery, Orders, Payments.

- I made after order functionalities such as reduce the quantify of sold products, send the order received email, clearing the cart, Order completion page as well as generating an invoice for the order.
- Also, I made a Review and Rating system where I designed the interactive rating stars that even allows to rate a half-star rating.
- I made my account functionalities for the customer who can easily edit his profile, profile pictures, change his account password, and also manage his orders.

Advanced Laravel Ecommerce 2

- It's an eCommerce application Using Laravel framework.
- I made my own custom user model, categories and products, Carts, Incrementing, Decrementing and removing cart items, Unlimited Product image gallery, Orders, Payments
- I made after order functionalities such as reduce the quantify of sold products, send the order received email, clearing the cart, Order completion page as well as generating an invoice for the order.
- Also, I made a Review and Rating system where I designed the interactive rating stars that even allows to rate a half-star rating.
- I made my account functionalities for the customer who can easily edit his profile, profile pictures, change his account password, and also manage his orders.

Advanced Django Ecommerce ☑

- It's an eCommerce application using Django framework.
- I made my own custom user model, categories and products, Carts, Incrementing, Decrementing and removing cart items, Unlimited Product image gallery, Orders, Payments
- I made after order functionalities such as reduce the quantify of sold products, send the order received email, clearing the cart, Order completion page as well as generating an invoice for the order.
- Also, I made a Review and Rating system where I designed the interactive rating stars that even allows to rate a half-star rating.
- I made my account functionalities for the customer who can easily edit his profile, profile pictures, change his account password, and also manage his orders.

Attendance 🛮

- This project is used to track the attendance of the employees of the company.
- As a new employee, I can register to the system & start using its functionality.
- Only signed-in employees can log their attendance.
- As an employee, I can log my new attendance and list the previous attendance records.
- Each employee lists attendance records related to himself only.
- Employee can't log attendance for another employee.
- Each attendance record shall have check-in & check-out times.
- Attendance validations:
 - Check-out can't be before check-in.
 - you can't log your check-out before logging the check-in first.
 - check-out time must be always bigger than check-in time.
 - User can't create attendance record for the same interval.

Study_buddy 2

- It is a website for people who study and want to share with others, so they create rooms, each room is about a specific topic,
- the room is called by the name of its topic, and any user can be a member in this room by simply participating in it.
- Every user has his own profile page which shows all the rooms he created and all the details of his account,
- Through which he can change his profile picture, email, username and if he forgot his password, he can reset it by sending a message to his email to reset it.

Skills

Programming Languages

- C++ / OOP
- PHP / OOP
- Python / OOP
- JavaScript
- Bash script

Database & Servers

- SQL
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- SQLite
- ORM

FrontEnd

- HTML5
- CSS3
- XML

Framework

- Laravel
- Django
- Odoo

Networking

CCNA (Routing and Switching)

DevOps

- Linux
- GIT
- AWS
- Docker
- Jenkins

Languages

English

Arabic

Fluent

Mother Tongue